Inventory of the Larry C. Bradley Jesse James Film Collection, 1918-1978
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Larry C. Bradley Jesse James film collection
1918-1978
Bradley, Larry C.
04103
2.21 cubic ft. (5 boxes + one oversized framed poster)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
The collection contains materials relating to the filming of the 1939 motion picture "Jesse James" and the film's director Henry King.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection has been divided into two series.
Biography of Larry C. Bradley
Larry C. Bradley was a Pineville, Missouri resident who wrote about Missouri history and was an avid collector of materials related to the 1939 Jesse James film.
History of Jesse James Film
"Jesse James" (1939) was a western movie directed by Henry King and starring Tyrone Power, Henry Fonda, Nancy Kelly, and Randolph Scott. Written by Nunnally Johnson, the film was loosely based on the life of the notorious outlaw from which the film derives its name. "Jesse James" was the fourth largest grossing movie of 1939, and was primarily filmed in Pineville, Missouri.
Scope and Content
The bulk of the Larry C. Bradley Jesse James Film collection contains items relating to Henry King's 1939 film "Jesse James" as well as other aspects of Henry King's career. These materials include promotional materials, periodicals, photographs, films, and TV special scripts.
Access Restrictions
On site use only. Copies and loans are permitted only with permission of donor.
Related Materials
Henry King papers (collection 2798) at the American Heritage Center.
Acquisition Information
This material was received from Larry C. Bradley from 1972-2010.
Access Terms
King, Henry, 1886-1982.; James, Jesse, 1847-1882--In motion pictures.;;; Pineville (Mo.);; Jesse James [Motion picture]
Arts, Humanities, and Social Sciences; Performing Arts; Social Life and Customs; People, Ethnicity, and Culture
Container List
- Series I. Jesse James Film (1939) and Henry King
  - Book - "The Hollywood Professionals, Volume 2: Henry King, Lewis Milestone, and Sam Wood,", 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Books and Booklets Related to "Jesse James" Film, 1970, 1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Concerning Henry King attending Jesse James Days, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fact Sheets - "Jesse James," "Jesse Jame...Anatomy of a Legend," and other Henry King Projects, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Henry King Biography and Filmography, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Henry King - "Henry King Comments" Script, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Henry King - "Henry King Comments" 16-mm Film (2 Reels), 1973 (Box 4)
  - Henry King - Photographs from Jesse James Days (6 Items), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Jesse James Days Negatives - Various Promotional Materials, undated (Box 3)
  - Jesse James Days Periodicals, 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Jesse James Days TV Specials Scripts, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Jesse James" Film - Ad Posters (9 1/2" x 7"), undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Jesse James" Film - Ad Poster (41" x 26 1/2"), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Jesse James" Film - Ad Poster, Framed (41" x 26 1/2"), 1951 (Oversized Item)
  - "Jesse James" Film - Advertisements, circa 1939 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Jesse James" Film - Autograph Book, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Jesse James" Film - Biographies of Stars, circa 1939 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Jesse James" Film - Color Slide (Damaged), undated (Box 3)
  - "Jesse James" Film - Lobby Cards (7 Items), 1946 (Box 3)
  - "Jesse James" Film - Outtakes, 16-mm Film (8 Reels), 1938 (Box 5)
  - "Jesse James" Film - Photographs (8 Items), 1938 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Jesse James" Film - Press Releases, circa 1938 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Jesse James" Film and Henry King Periodicals, 1938-1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Series II. Miscellaneous Materials
  - "Great Northfield Minnesota Raid" Film - Ad Poster, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Jesse James Articles, 1938-1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Periodicals, 1918-1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Printed Materials - Missouri (General), 1972-1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Additional Container Lists
  The American Heritage Center is in the process of converting its older container lists to a more accessible format. This link is to an older version of a container list.
  - Link to Accessioning Worksheet (PDF), Link to Content List (PDF)